CARRIER SUMMERY

10+ Years of experience in IT sector including various industries like E – Learning, Electronics and Communication, Finance, Pharma etc. with various technologies like Web Designing and Development, Marketing Automation, Campaign Management, Database Marketing, Data Optimization and Governance, Team Management and Lead

Experience in designing email templates and landing pages using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and configuring campaigns with various channels including Email, Onsite, Mobile Push, Incentive etc. using various campaign building tools like IBM Unica, Picasso Notebooks and SFMC.

Able to work independently to personalize content for customers basis on their behavior/segment/past contact history in IBM Unica e – message, SFMC content builder using AMPScript, SSJS and Dynamic content configuration

Expert in handling client requirements and E2E client communication, building target audience for campaigns using SQL, Teradata, BigQuery or other third-party data tools, data cleaning and segmentation

Expert is setting customer journeys using IBM Unica Segmentation and SFMC Journey builder tools to send right communication at the right time to right customers Also, able to work independently on campaign reporting to track campaign responses to measure ROI and to build future forecasting, reports using SQL or SFMC tracking, out of the box reporting and data intelligence, data views features

In depth knowledge of Salesforce CRM eco system, Oracle, CPQ and how to configure a product to get the Quotation to share with customer for a specific product using Quote to order conversion

CONTACT

PHONE: 9540676479/9813884219 ADDRESS: H90, GF, Village & Post Office – Khatod, Landmark – Near Panchayat

SHISHPAL YADAV

Senior Associate | Campaign Management | SFMC

WORK EXPERIENCE

Indegene Inc., Client AMGEN – Senior Associate | Campaign Management (SFMC) Sept 2022 – Current

- Working in team of 6 peoples where I am primarily responsible for creating target audience and configuring campaigns on SFMC followed by the standard QA Process
- Independently responsible for creating a data source for a campaign within SFMC using automation studio SQL query basis on the client requirement
- Independently responsible for creating and configuring campaigns with user initiated/triggered/journey using the journey builder within SFMC
- Responsible to configure E2E email using AMPScript and SSJS wherever required for the email personalization
- Responsible for campaign reporting and tracking post campaign launch

Genpact Headstrong Capital Markets, Client PayPal – Principal Consultant Dec 2018 – Sept 2022

- Closely working with stake holders including various marketers, scrum master and different teams including Email, Web, Onsite ops on day 2-day basis and helping them to understand the new requirements and provide them best possible solution to get their job done
- Working on various kind of campaigns following the Agile WoW which includes Email, Onsite, Paid Media and Incentive and getting the data for targeting after understanding the requirement
- Performing E2E testing for campaigns before going live and helping in trouble shooting in case of any failure/error
- Handling a team of ~ 10 peoples and helping to make them comfortable with the process/getting more process knowledge with experience gained so far and by resolving their queries if they have any
- Performing campaign post launch activities like creating reports to check CTR, Open/Click responses, email sent timings, Payouts etc. using SQL, Tableau and Excel
- Building campaigns on SFMC using Data Extensions, Audience Builder, Email Studio, Automation Studio and Journey Builder

Keysight Technologies - Business Support Program Specialist Dec 2014 – Dec 2018

- Involved in E2E campaign building process including requirement gathering, building emails, creating segmentation, campaign testing, launching, scheduling, and campaign monitoring/reporting post-launch
- Worked on Salesforce CRM as an end user, where I was responsible for E2E testing with different roles like Field Engineer, Customer Service Representative

Bhawan/Govt. school, District – Mahendragarh, State – Haryana, PIN - 123029

EMAIL: itsmeshishpal@gmail.com

SKILLS AND EXPERINCE

- Web designing and Development (2 Yrs.)
 - HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap
- Campaign Management (8 Yrs.)
 - IBM Unica (5 Yrs.), Picasso Notebooks (2 Yrs.), SFMC (1 Yr.)
- Data Base (6 Yrs.)
 - SQL, Teradata, Big Query
- Salesforce CRM, CPQ, Oracle DBA (Quote to order conversion)
- Programming Languages (2 Yrs.)
 - C#, Dot Net, Python

TRAINING/CERTIFICATION/AWARDS

- 6 Months .Net training from HCL
- Lean Six Sigma Certified
- SFMC Email Specialist
- SFMC Administrator
- SFMC Developer
- Received Best Performer Award from Client as well as Company

PROJECTS

Job Search Website in College Project using HTML, Dot Net and C#

ACHIEVEMENTS/PROCESS ENHANCEMENT

- Helped client in migrating welcome offer where we were targeting customers who signed up via App, Web or MS from old legacy process where there was delay in data refresh from 24 – 48 hrs. to real time using client applications where the data can be seen in the real time or as soon as a new customer signs up into the system that helped in doubled the NNA's.
 - Helped in creating the data to target the customers in real time
 - Worked with the risk team to identify the risky customers to mitigate the risk
 - Suggested other work arounds as well to client like delayed payout/ Payout reversal for risky customers to avoid risk factors

HOBBIES — Reading, Playing, watching movies, Cooking, Exercising

- etc. to test any new requirement whether the flow is working fine or not after each Salesforce update
- Worked on Oracle for Quote to Order conversion and to send the final quotation to the customer who will be interested in buying a new product or interested in buying any part for any of their product

Mynd Solutions Private Limited, Client Agilent Technologies - Web Support Developer

Apr 2014 - Dec 2014

Worked in building responsive customer emails which work well on all smartphone devices considering the various browser compatibility parameters in mind

FCS Software Solutions Limited, Client Canon India and Canon Singapore – Junior Developer

Dec 2012 - Mar 2014

- Primary work was to convert Adobe Flash E-Learning courses into Mobile compatible/Responsive using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, JavaScript and Bootstrap, etc. so, that they can easily been seen on any of the smart pone devices like Android and Apple/iOS
- Worked on designing broachers, email templates, images using Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator tools for client to use in their E – Leaning projects
- Worked for one of the biggest clients NLB Academy Singapore to build their flash courses on HTML5. And was part of some inhouse projects as well for Cannon Singapore

EDUCATION

B-Tech, CSE, Maharshi Dayanand University (Rohtak)

2007 - 2011 with First Division

CBSE New Delhi

2004 – 2006 Secondary and Senior Secondary (PCM) with First Division